Saurabh Kumar

Phone:7974689632 email:saurabhkumar25022015@gmail.com



Saurabh-kumar-01993416b



saurabhsk77

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am a software Engineer having 1 year of experience with strong desire to apply education to root cause analysis in product development. Committed to successful project rollouts with ability to work with all types of personalities. Background working with cutting-edge technologies and emerging concepts.

EXPERIENCE

Persistent Systems ,Bengaluru,India

DEC 2020-PRESENT

- Designation: Software Engineer
- Directed software design and development across multifaceted team to Meet client needs for functionality, timeline and performance.

EduBridge Learning Pvt. Ltd.,Bengaluru,India

DEC 2019-FEB 2020

- Winter Internship
- Java Full stack developer Intern
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback On different stages and directly addressed concerns.

Karunadu Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru, India

JUL 2019-AUG 2019

- Summer Internship
- Python with machine learning Intern
- Project: Car price prediction
- Domain: Machine learning

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Working Knowledge

- Language: Java, Javascript ,React js , HTML ,CSS
- Database : MySQL ,Oracle ,Mongodb
- Technologies: SQL , SASS/SCSS
- Tools: GIT, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse Material UI, ,styled components
- CI/CD : Jenkins
- Operating System : Windows ,macOS

Areas of Interest

Database designing, Web Development, Data Science

EDUCATION

Sambhram Institute of technology(VTU),Bengaluru,India

AUG 2016-SEPT 2020

- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science
- CGPA: 8.16

Kendriya Vidyalaya Bengdubi, Siliguri, India

APR 2015-MAR 2016

- High Secondary School (12th)
- Percentage: 79.1
- Elected as School Captain.

Kendriya Vidyalaya Bengdubi, Siliguri, India

APR 2013-MAR 2014

• SSLC(10TH)- CGPA: 10.00

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Project Title: Restaurant Management User interface

- Technology: HTML ,CSS ,JAVASCRIPT ,REACT JS
- API : fetch ,axios
- Tools: visual studio code, react DevTools.

Project Title: Google Home Page User Interface cloning

Technology: HTML ,CSSTools: visual studio code

Project Title: Facial recognition & Emotion Detection

- · Language: Python
- Tools: visual studio code, Jupyter notebook, Anaconda prompt
- Designed a facial recognition system using support vector machine, which can identify the real time face using the trained image from the database.

Project Title: Covid-19 Cases Tracking UI

- Language: Python , HTML ,CSS ,JAVASCRIPT
- IDE : Jupyter Notebook
- Designed a mini project that helps in finding the total number of cases in a particular country by using the covid package. The project also display the pie chart of the total cases, active and recovered cases.

Project Title: Airline Management system

- Language: c#, MySQL
- Framework: .NET
- Designed a mini project that deals with both the user and the admin interface in accessing
 respective details and facilities to be required in airport starting from the booking of flight
 ticket to the entry of employee details by the administration.

ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATION

- Front End development using React certification from udemy.
- Java basics certification from HACKERRANK & SOLOLEARN.
- Data Science essential certification from LETSUPGRADE.
- Recipient of Prime minister Scholarship.
- KVS national science congress (3rd at regional level)
- Participated in national sports meet (cricket)
- National youth parliament (Govt. of India)-1st

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Nationality: Indian

• Date of Birth: 08/07/1999

• Languages Known: Hindi, English (written and proficiency)

DECLARATION

I therefore pronounce that all data given above is consistent with the best of my insight.

Date:

Place: Bengaluru (Saurabh Kumar)